《指定幸存者》前情提要
Previously on "Designated Survivor"...
副总统彼得·麦克利什
Vice President Peter MacLeish was shot and killed
被他的妻子贝丝·麦克利什开枪射杀
by his wife, Beth MacLeish.
之后 贝丝调转枪口
She then turned the gun upon herself
饮弹自杀
and committed suicide.
你始终都是袭击目标
You are a target.
我希望我们的孩子过正常人的生活
I want our kids to have a normal life.
我和迈克商量了总统行宫
I spoke with Mike about Camp David.
他说那里守卫更森严
He says it's more secure.
摩斯总统想重回政坛吗
President Moss wants to get back into politics.
他只是想分享他成功的经验
He just wants to share the benefit of his experience.
邀请他来白宫就职可以让国家走出低迷
Inviting him into the White House could lift the nation,
让人民感受到团结的力量
project a sense of solidarity.
我会安排的
I'll set it up.
也许你需要休息一下
Maybe you need some personal time.
- 大概一周左右的时间  - 是 总统先生
- Take maybe a week.  - Yes, sir.
我希望你能做我的代理幕僚长
I would like you to be my acting chief of staff.
我不会让您失望的
I won't let you down.
亚伦
Aaron?
亚伦·肖尔和某个人碰面了
Aaron Shore's made contact with someone.
是查尔斯·兰登
That's Charles Langdon.
到底怎么回事 我以为你死了 查理
What the hell's going on? I thought you were dead, Charlie.
跟我走就行
Just follow me.
他们躲进了第十大街的圣安吉洛教堂
They just ducked into St. Angelo's on 10th.
收到 守住北门 我们马上到
Copy. Cover the north entrance. We're a minute out.
请站起来祈福
Please rise for the blessing.
大家一起祷告
Let us pray.
- 现在进去  - 收到
We go now.  Copy that.
查理 你得告诉我 这是怎么回事
Charlie, you got to tell me what's going on.
听着 我只有一分钟时间
Just listen. I've only got a minute.
我要你帮我做件事 这决定了我的生死
I need you to do something for me. My life depends on it.
走 走
Go. Go.
- 肖尔  - 威尔士探员
- Shore!  - Agent Wells?
兰登在哪里
Where's Langdon?
他走了 我甚至没…
H-He took off. I didn't even...
- 哪个门  - 他从那边走了
- Which door?  - He walked out that way.
待着别动
Stay there!
- 亨德里克斯  - 哪个门没人守
Hendricks!  Which door isn't covered?
东门
East side.
谢谢你艾娃
Thank you, Ava.
总统先生 见到你不用拄拐杖了真好
Mr. President, it's nice to see you without the cane.
- 你肯定好多了  - 是好多了谢谢
You must be feeling better.  I am. Thank you.
我们制作了一份剪短的副总统候选人名单
We're compiling a short list of VP candidates
供你查阅
for you to look over,
还有一些候选内阁成员
as well as more potential cabinet appointees.
不幸的是 选择仍然有限 先生
Unfortunately, it's still slim pickings, sir.
大部分人对于加入新政府
Most people are very apprehensive
感到非常不安
about joining the new administration.
有太多不确定因素了
There's just too much uncertainty.
希望前总统摩斯能帮到我们
Well, hopefully, former President Moss
他承诺给我们一份人员名单
can help with that... He promised a list of names
并答应会使尽浑身解数说服他们
and to throw his weight around until they said yes.
我是明天见他 对吗
I'm seeing him tomorrow, right?
对 会面安排在中午
Yes. Your meeting is set for midday.
我也在您的住处安排了一次非正式晚宴
I've also set up an informal dinner
并邀请了第一夫人出席
at the Residence with the First Lady.
除非…当然了 她不能出席
Unless, of course, she's not available.
不 不 她会出席的
No, no, no. She'll be there.
这么说来 您是摩斯总统的粉丝吗
I take it you're a fan of President Moss?
事实上在他第一次竞选期间 我到处发广告
I handed out yard signs during his first campaign, actually.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你和兰登保持联系有多久了
So, how long have you and Langdon been in contact?
我们没有联系过
We haven't been in contact.
我跟你说了 我以为他死了
I told you I thought he was dead.
他只是在街上靠近我而己
He just walked up to me on the street.
然而 你跟他走了
And yet, you went with him.
我还能怎么做
What was I gonna do?
我要知道他所说过的每字每句
I need to know word-for-word what he said.
不要遗漏任何细节
Don't leave anything out.
好的 但他也没说太多
Okay, but he didn't say much.
他…他极度警惕
He... He was extremely paranoid...
一直战战兢兢 不断地左顾右盼
Just constantly looking over his shoulder
像是正在被追杀之类的
like he was being hunted or something.
他说 这决定了他的生死
He said his life depended on it.
兰登想要做个交易
Langdon wants a deal?
是的 总统先生 以情报换取豁免权
Yes, sir... immunity in exchange for information.
还要终生受到证人保护
And a new life in witness protection.
不可能
That's not gonna happen.
兰登唯一能争取到的是活命的机会
The only thing Langdon has left to bargain for is his life.
你们认为他都知道些什么
What kind of information do you think he has?
总统先生 我们还不知道
Sir, we don't know yet,
但他是我们与这场阴谋间的唯一联系
but he's our only known connection to the conspiracy.
他的消息可能会非常有用
Information from him could be invaluable.
也可能毫无价值 我们都知道
Or not... I mean, for all we know,
他可能仍然与策划者为伍
he could still be working with the conspirators.
兰登在爆炸案后曾多次联系过我
Langdon contacted me several times after the bombing.
是他指引我调查麦克利什的 要不是他
He's the one that put me onto MacLeish. Without him...
我可能早死了
I'd probably be dead.
总统先生 我整个职业生涯
Mr. President, I've spent my entire career
都在抓捕那些看似无辜
tracking down stone-cold criminals
实际上却杀人不眨眼的冷血罪犯
who'd make you swear they were as pure as driven snow.
我们需要更多的证据
We need more information.
如果条件允许 我们可以那样做
And in a perfect world, we would have that.
但我们没时间了
We don't have time.
肖尔必须在二十四个小时内给他答复
Shore was given 24 hours to respond.
如果不抓住这次机会 兰登就会消失
If we don't use it, Langdon's in the wind.
这可能是个陷阱
This could be a giant setup.
你说他已是四处逃命的惊弓之鸟
You said he's running scared.
把他带来
Bring him in.
指定幸存者
第一季 第十四集
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
- 早上好  - 早上好 那是什么
- Morning.  - Morning. What is that?
这是防弹背心
This is a bulletproof vest.
翻译     Sienna  桃子  尼基塔
我知道它是防弹背心 你为什么拿着它
I know what it is. Why do you have it?
这其实只是摆设而己
It's really just ceremonial,
翻译     子V  胡说大王  薇薇安
但每一任的新闻发言人都会将它
but, uh, each press secretary passes this on down
传给下一任的新闻发言人
to the next press secretary,
翻译     silence  酥K  长颈鹿
并且我认为 既然你现在是代理幕僚长
and I figured, since you're now acting chief of staff,
借你用一下也未尝不可
maybe a loan was in order.
翻译     星星与野狗  pang  潇然
我是艾米丽·罗迪斯
Emily Rhodes.
我马上过去
I'm on my way.
校对     长颈鹿  MQ小早
你想让我把它挂在哪里
You want me to hang this up somewhere?
我不需要
I'm good.
- 什么 你不要吗  - 不过还是要谢谢你
What, you don't want it?  Thanks, though.
时间轴     Avis  姜姜  壬虚浪影
那好吧
Fine.
非洲事务局
行动建议   纳鲁巴
后期     虫虫不咬人
总监     MQ小早
声明     人人视频与字幕组无关 请勿混淆
早上好 总统先生
Good morning, Mr. President.
纳鲁巴那边的状况
This situation in Naruba...
你了解多少
What do you know about it?
一位游击军阀撕毁了与政府的停战协议
A guerilla warlord broke a cease-fire with the government.
他叫阿特苏·卡拉米
His name's Atsu Kalame.
他手下的民兵达一万人
He's got a militia force 10,000 strong.
众所周知 他所开展的恐怖活动包括有
He's known to utilize child soldiers,
征募儿童兵 对平民进行截肢
mass amputations, and human trafficking
及贩卖等非人道迫害行为
as part of his terror campaign.
我曾在那附近的和平工作团工作过
I served near there in the Peace Corps,
25年
25...
不止25年前了
more than 25 years ago.
他们是我见过的最为善良的一群人
They were some of the kindest people I've ever known.
简报中提到很多家庭涌到边境
The brief said families are racing to the borders,
试图逃离家园
trying to escape.
简直无法想象
I can't even imagine.
联系要员 我们必须采取相关措施
Reach out to State. We need to do something.
好的 总统先生
Yes, sir.
兰登先生
Mr. Langdon.
你想让我从何讲起
Where do you want me to start?
从头开始讲吧
How about the beginning?
好的那就要从克劳汀说起
Okay. The beginning would be Claudine.
克劳汀·波因特
Uh... Claudine Poyet.
四年前 我们在子午线宴会上认识
We met at the Meridian Ball four years ago.
那时候我刚离婚
I was coming off a nasty divorce at the time.
我以为那是真爱
I thought I was in love.
但很明显 她想的并不一样
Clearly, she had other things in mind.
当我搞清楚情况的时候…
When I found out what was going on...
你一定要相信我
You've got to believe me
我发现之后曾试图阻止这一切
that when I figured it out, I tried to stop it.
我失去了朋友
I mean, those were my friends that died,
失去了我的总统
that was my president that died,
多希望我那时能和他们一起死掉
and I wish I had died with them!
好吧
Okay.
一开始只是很小的事情
At first, it was just little things.
她为一家大型承包商工作
She... She worked for a big contracting firm.
至少她是这样说的
At least, she said she did.
她让我帮她收集一些关于
And so she asked me to help her get some Intel
政府高速公路合同的信息
on some government highway contract.
好一阵子都是这类小事
It was that sort of thing for a while.
之后她就要求查看国会大厦翻修的
And then she asked to see the threat assessment
威胁评估报告
on the Capitol renovation.
105号房
Room 105.
你竟然没有起疑心吗
And that didn't make you suspicious?
那可是叛国罪 兰登
That's treason, Langdon.
不是的
No. No!
那时候谁能想得到他们会利用这些信息
Who could imagine that they would've used that information
来制造如此可怕的袭击
in that way at the time?
我之所以还没有给自己脑袋来一枪
The only reason I haven't put a bullet in my head
是因为我觉得自己或许能帮得上忙
is the thought that maybe I could help...
能将功补过
make this right.
不然你认为我为什么会在这里
Why else do you think I'm here?
克劳汀·波因特
Claudine Poyet...
我怎么知道是否真有其人
How do I know she really exists?
我有照片
I have a picture.
我有她的照片
I have a picture of her.
她不喜欢拍照
She hated having her picture taken,
但某天早上 她还在睡觉
but one morning, she was, uh, sleeping,
然后
and...
我拍了这个
I took this.
就是她
That's her.
那就是她
孔特雷拉斯将军 感谢你的到来
General Contreras. Thank you for joining.
地面情况如何
What is the situation on the ground?
我们有不到三小时前的卫星照片 长宫
We've got satellite photos less than three hours old, sir.
卡拉米和他的反叛军
They put Kalame and his rebel forces
大约在距离首都首济两天路程开外
approximately two days out from the capital city of Soji,
没有任何武装力量能阻挡他们
with nothing in between to stop them.
我会联系联合国大使
I'll reach out to the U.N. Ambassador.
可能他比我更能说服
Maybe he'll have better luck than I did
联合国安理会投票举行投票决议
convincing the Security Council to vote on a resolution.
为什么联合国没有动静
Why is the U.N. dragging their feet?
俄罗斯曾使用否决权阻止
Russia has been protesting possible
联合国干预乌克兰
U.N. involvement with Ukraine.
他们很有可能会否决一切维和行动
They're likely to veto all peacekeeping moves.
这很有可能演变成种族屠杀
This has all the markings of a potential genocide.
- 是的长官  - 我无法接受
Yes, sir.  Well, that's not acceptable to me.
你是在建议进行军事打击吗
- Are you proposing a military response?
可能吧 我希望一个小时之内看到
Maybe. I want all my options on the table...
武力或其他手段的所有可行方案
Military or otherwise... Within the hour.
就这样
That'll be all.
长官 摩斯总统已经到了
Sir, President Moss is arriving now.
好的
Okay.
早上好
Morning.
Good morning.
近来还好吗 先生们
How are you, gentlemen?
总统先生 欢迎回来
Mr. President. Welcome back.
谢谢 亲爱的
Thank you, dear.
总统先生 荣幸至极
Mr. President, it's an honor.
很高兴见到你
Nice to see you.
欢迎回来 总统先生
Welcome back, Mr. President.
亨利 孩子们怎么样了
Henry. How are the kids?
萨拉现在有53岁了吧
Sara must be, what... 53 now?
快22岁了 先生
Close... 22, sir.
一眨眼就长大了啊 亨利 是吧
Blink of an eye, Henry. Am I right?
您说得对 总统先生
You are indeed, Mr. President.
总统先生
Mr. President.
摩斯总统
President Moss.
总统先生
Mr. President.
很荣幸能请您到这儿来 先生
It's an honor to have you here, sir.
谢谢 艾娃
Thank you, Ava.
风景不改啊 对吗
Ah. View never gets old, does it?
不知道 我才刚入驻没多久
I don't know. I-I haven't been here that long yet.
确实
Indeed.
终于能跟您面对面交流
I can't tell you how special it is
我无法描述内心的激动
to finally meet you face-to-face.
我想告诉您
And I want you to know that
我愿意接受您给我提的任何建议
I am open to hearing any advice that you have to offer.
我的前任总统给我的第一个建议就是
Well...first piece of advice my predecessor gave me was,
“不要听任何前任总统给你的建议”
"Don't listen to the advice of your predecessor."
我会好好考虑的
Well, I'll take that under advisement.
言归正传
All joking aside,
我很敬仰您 先生
I look up to you, sir,
我很想知道您对我
and I would love to hear
到目前为止的表现是如何评价的
how you think I'm doing so far.
你还是不知道的好
No, you wouldn't.
什么
I-I'm sorry?
要我说实话吗
Total honesty?
当然
Yes... always.
交到你手上的是一份极为艰巨的工作
You were handed an impossible job, son...
在过去 你并无实权
A political non-entity,
从未参加竞选 也未曾服过兵役
never ran for office, never served in uniform,
在一场史无前例的危机中
suddenly thrust into the most powerful job
突然被推上了权倾四海之位
in the world during an unprecedented crisis.
你本来就不该对自己有多大期望
Hell, you shouldn't have expected much of yourself.
人民也不该对你有多大期望
And the people shouldn't have, either.
毕竟是我要您说实话
Well...I asked for honesty.
别误会
Well, don't get me wrong.
你的进步很大
You've made some great strides.
我给你个及格吧
I give you a passing grade, professor.
但在处理马吉德·纳萨尔这件事上
But, uh, the handling of Majid Nassar,
还有那位田径教练被逮捕之时
the way you let the Russians play you like a fiddle
你竟任由俄罗斯将你玩弄于股掌之中
when it came to that damn track coach,
更不用提那位己故的副总统
not to mention our late vice president
下令联调局射杀那个试图刺杀你的人
ordering the FBI to kill the man who tried to kill you.
有传闻说这绝非巧合
Company scuttlebutt is that that was no coincidence.
此事还在调查中 先生
That's an ongoing investigation, sir.
不 不 我明白
Oh, no, no. I get it.
相信我 我懂的
Believe me, I do.
治理好这个国家是最为艰巨的任务
Running this country is the hardest job there is.
问题是 这一切砸到你脸上的时候
Problem is, with everything that's been flying at you,
你却没有随机应变
you're not actually running it.
你是在被动应付 而非主动出击
You're reacting, not leading.
但正如我所说的 你面对的火力太猛了
But it's like I said... You were simply outgunned.
不要对自己太过苛责
So don't be too hard on yourself.
我不会的 总统先生
I won't, Mr. President.
希望您能对我进行苛责
I'll let you take care of that.
我听说 您会提供一些名字给我
I'm told you had some names for me...
内阁职位候选人
Cabinet positions.
当然
I sure as hell do.
这些都是可用之才
Now, these are some damn fine people,
他们肯定能助你渡过难关
and I think they'll be able to help you out.
谢谢
Thank you.
你这儿有威特基[威士忌品牌]吗
You, uh, got any Wild Turkey lying about?
以前我会在那个抽屉里放几瓶
I used to keep some in that drawer.
没有 抱歉
No, I'm sorry.
各有所好
Each his own.
介意我打给厨房吗
Mind if I call the kitchen?
没问题 打吧
Sure. Go ahead.
近来如何
Yeah. How are you?
这有点恐怖 这是什么
Uh, okay, this is scary. What is it?
这是你在2015年6月23日撤回的
This is the threat assessment file you had recalled
威胁评估文件
on June 23, 2015.
你到底在说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
这份文件又是谁做的
Who even generated this file?
高级政府官员还没来得及
You had this file electronically retrieved
研究这份文件
from a list of top government officials
你就通过电脑把它撤回了
before they had a chance to study it.
那好吧 这能说得通
W-Well, okay, that would explain it.
如果是我通过电脑的话 我就不会看到内容
If I did it electronically, I never would've seen this.
但是你却记得把它撤回了
But you remember withdrawing it?
当…当然不是
Well, o-of course not!
兰登让我帮他做了很多事情
Langdon asked me to do a number of things,
相信我 如果我看过这类文件的话
and believe me, if I would've seen something like this,
我一定会有印象的
I would remember it.
艾米丽查我的通话记录就是为了这个吗
Is this why Emily was snooping through my phone records?
你说呢
You tell me.
你们之前在跟踪兰登
Well, you were tailing Langdon.
为什么不直接找他问清楚呢
Why didn't you just pick him up and ask him yourself?
我们不是在跟踪兰登
We weren't tailing Langdon.
我是不是得找个律师
I mean, do I need an attorney?
你随时都可以离开这里
You're free to walk anytime.
现在 你只是这起调查的友好证人
Right now, you're just a friendly witness in an investigation...
仅此而己
Nothing more.
没错 但是你们在跟踪我
Yeah, but you were following me.
肖尔先生 联调局正在调查的是一个
Mr. Shore, the Bureau's investigating the greatest crime
试图倾覆美国政府的史无前例的阴谋
ever committed against the government of the United States.
如果你能帮助我们了解这件事的话
If you can contribute to our understanding,
你将功德无量
it would be a great service.
所以 我再问你一遍
So let me ask you again.
请你再认真仔细地回想
To the best of your memory,
关于这份文件 你能给我们什么信息
what can you tell us about this file?
- 欢迎回家  - 你怎么样
Welcome back.  How are you?
- 我挺好的  - 你没事吧
- I'm all right. - You okay?
我真的很想你
I really missed you.
得了吧 我才走了一天
Come on. I was only gone for a day.
我知道 只是…感觉不止一天
I know. It just... feels longer than that.
- 孩子们呢  - 很好
- How are the kids?  - Good.
佩妮喜欢上了骑马
Penny has discovered horseback riding.
那可真快
That was fast.
而且她已经决定了在她生日的时候
And she's already decided that she's gonna ask you
要你送她一匹小马
to buy her a pony for her birthday.
什么时候都可以啊
Well, she can always ask.
- 李奥呢  - 他很好
How's Leo?  He's really good.
这件事真的让他成长许多
This has really made him grow up, you know?
我为他感到骄傲
I'm proud of him.
他明白 这只是暂时的 对吧
He understands that this is temporary, right?
他们俩都知道
I mean, they both know
等一切都平息过后 他们就能回来了对吧
that this is just until everything calms down?
嗯 他们知道
Yeah, they know.
好的
Okay, good.
你妈妈怎么样了
How is your mother?
我代她向你问候
She sends her love.
她还是希望我是个医生吗
She still wish I was a doctor?
快翻篇吧
You got to let that go.
你永远都不会让她满意的 她可是俄罗斯人
You're never gonna impress her. She's Russian.
和科内留斯·摩斯的会面怎么样
So, how was Cornelius Moss?
- 和我预想的不太一样  - 怎么说
- Uh, that went a little differently than I expected.  - How so?
我以为他会同情我的处境
I thought he'd be a little more sympathetic to my situation.
那我们得在晚宴的时候向他施展点魅力了
Well, we'll just have to charm him at dinner tonight.
进来
Come in.
抱歉 总统先生 该出发了
Sorry, sir. It's time to go.
我马上过去
I'll be right there.
坐下 查理
Sit down, Charlie.
你要为那一千多条人命负责
You're responsible for the deaths of over 1,000 people...
他们都是这个国家的领导人
The leaders of this country.
我不知道会发生这样的事
I had no idea what was going to happen.
我怎么会知道整个政府
How could I know that the entire government
会被彻底击垮
was going to be taken out?
我不是禽兽
I'm not a monster.
你不知道
You had no idea?!
你和彼得·麦克利什是在爆炸中仅存的两个人
You and Peter MacLeish were the only two to survive the bombing!
这你作何解释
How do you explain that?
因为我根本不在场
Because I was never there.
我发誓 我都告诉他们了
I swear. I've told them everything.
告诉我
Tell me.
国情咨文演说那天
On the day of the State of the Union,
我接到了一个我才看清真面目的女人的电话
I got a phone call from a woman I'd come to know...
她声称手上有我的把柄
...who had blackmail information on me.
并说还有最后一个任务要给我
She said she had one last job for me to do.
是什么
What was it?
她想让我任命你为指定幸存者
She wanted me to name you Designated Survivor.
她为什么要我做指定幸存者
Why did she want me named as the Designated Survivor?
我拒绝了 她不肯告诉我原因
When I refused to make the call, she wouldn't tell me.
- 少来  - 我说的是实话
Not good enough.  I am telling you the truth.
如果不是你做的决定 那是谁
If you didn't make the call, who did?
我不知道 不过肯定是有足够权限
I don't know, but it must have been somebody
做这种决定的人
with enough clearance to make that move.
简直是浪费时间
This is a waste of time.
总统先生 请听他说完
Sir. Please hear him out.
她说如果我拒绝 我就死定了
She said if I refused, I was a dead man...
喂
Yes?
到处都是他们的眼线
...and that they had eyes everywhere.
然后她说出了我当时的领带颜色
And then she told me the color of the tie I was wearing.
我可是在我的办公室里
I was in my office
在世界上最安全的建筑里
in the most secure building on the planet,
而她却知道我的领带是什么颜色
and she knows what color my tie is.
所以我挂了电话
So I hung up.
我不再在乎那些敲诈
I didn't care about the blackmail anymore.
我只知道我必须得在他们抓住我之前
I knew I just had to tell somebody what I knew
把我知道的一切说出去
before they got to me.
显然 白宫已经不再安全
Clearly, the White House wasn't safe anymore,
所以我匆忙离开了
so I got the hell out of there.
我上了车
I got to my car, and I...
立刻开走
I just... started to drive.
我不知道能信任谁
I didn't know who to trust.
后来我想到只能去找联调局
But then I realized it had to be the FBI.
我必须得亲自去见联调局局长
I had to get to the director himself,
所以我立刻前往亚历山德里亚市
so I went straight for Alexandria.
就在我快到的时候
And I almost made it...
我的车失控了
...when I lost control of my car.
他们应该是黑入了我的车
Yeah. They'd hacked it somehow.
最新海外影视剧下载
我被甩出了车
I was thrown clear of the car,
摔得不省人事
and I was knocked unconscious.
我挣扎着走到街上
I made my way up to the street.
就看见在国会大厦那边
And that's when I saw the orange glow
燃起了熊熊烈焰
on the horizon where the Capitol used to be...
成了一片火海…
and the f-flames and the...
我知道我失败了
And I knew I failed.
所以我逃走了
So, yeah, I ran.
从那时开始 我便四处逃命
And I've been running ever since.
我为什么要相信你所说的
Why should I believe any of this?
先生 我们查过了国情咨文演讲时的
Sir, we checked the surveillance footage from the
监控录像
State of the Union.
没有他在现场的记录
There's no record of him being there.
潜水队调查了那条河
A dive team checked the river.
找到了车
They found the car.
让我跟他单独谈谈
Give me the room for a minute, please.
迈克 没事的
Mike, it's all right.
你要知道 在我看来
You should know, as far as I'm concerned,
就算不是你策划的 你也是同谋
even if you didn't do the planning, you're complicit.
你想要用你的生命来跟我做交易
You want to make a deal for your life with me,
我想要的不止这些
I expect more.
我知道的都告诉你了
I've told you everything I know.
最后一次机会
Last chance.
谁想让我成为指定幸存者 为什么
Who wanted me as the Designated Survivor and why?
我不知道 汤姆
I don't know, Tom.
总统先生 我很抱歉
Mr. President, I'm sorry,
但是我真的不知道是谁
but I don't know who.
至于为什么 我自己也在想这个问题
As to why, I wondered that myself.
你不会喜欢我的想法的
You're not gonna like this,
但我最好的推断是内阁成员中
but the best I can figure is that out of all our cabinet members...
你是最没能力当总统的
...you were the least qualified to be president.
我不知道这个阴谋的目的何在
So, I don't know what the goal of this conspiracy is.
为了改变格局 或只是为了无政府状态
Is it a regime change? Maybe it's just anarchy.
无论他们是什么思路
Whatever their philosophy...
很可能他们都觉得你是最不可能
they probably felt you were the least likely
成为阻碍的人
to present an obstacle.
给我一份非洲司令部的单页报告
Get me a one-pager on Africom
放出消息 说白宫正在
and let the room know that the White House
密切监控纳鲁巴的局势
is closely monitoring the situation in Naruba.
总统非常重视此事
The president is taking this very seriously.
赛斯 你有空吗
Uh, Seth, you got a sec?
很忙 怎么了
Barely. What's up?
有个朋友给我讲了件很奇怪的事
I got a friend that told me a strange story.
什么样的朋友
What kind of friend?
有足够安全等级的那种
Uh, the kind with security clearance.
好吧
Okay.
她在政府办公室分区做分析员
She's an analyst at this government office park
位于亚历山大市
out in Alexandria.
她说亚伦·肖尔被联邦调查局特工
She says Aaron Shore was escorted into the facility
带进局里了
by FBI agents.
你的朋友在骗你玩
Your friend's yanking your chain.
他放假去了 办理私事
He's on leave... Personal time.
是吗 是什么事情
Oh, yeah? What's that about?
我刚刚告诉你了
I just told you.
谢谢你 跑来这一趟
Thanks for stopping by.
我会想方法弄清楚的 赛斯
I find out otherwise, Seth,
这会登上新闻
this is gonna be a story.
到时候我会说你否认了
And I'm gonna say you denied it.
您随意
Knock yourself out.
俄罗斯无视了我和联合国大使的强烈要求
Despite my urgings and those of the U.N. Ambassador,
否决了安全理事会请求
Russia vetoed the Security Council vote
把维和部队遣回纳鲁巴的投票
to send peacekeepers back to Naruba.
我们还有什么选择
What are our options?
总统先生
Mr. President,
纳鲁巴是地球上最贫穷的国家之一
Naruba's one of the poorest countries on the planet.
附近的友好国家都
Friendly governments in the region
没兴趣插手
lack the interest to take this on.
那我们还能怎么办
Where does that leave us?
最好的办法就是我们从埃塞俄比亚和吉布提
Best option... we fly in Reaper hunter-killer UAVs
调遣收割者猎杀无人机过去
from Ethiopia and Djibouti to take out
铲除卡拉米的反叛势力和他的护卫
Kalame's rebel forces and his convoy.
那些导弹可以阻止事态发展 总统先生
Those missiles would stop the advance, sir.
这样会导致反叛力量的大范围伤亡
We could expect heavy rebel casualties.
无人机要多久能抵达目标上空
How much time till the UAVs are above their target?
六个小时
Six hours.
反叛势力要多久能入侵首都
How long till the rebel forces are in the capital?
一天 或者更短
A day... maybe less.
如果你想留下选择的余地 总统先生
If you want to keep your options open, sir,
我建议我们现在就让无人机起飞
I suggest we get those UAVs off the ground now.
我同意
I agree.
就这么办
Let's do it.
肖尔先生
Mr. Shore?
你可以走了
You're free to go.
很好
Good.
我办公室的人都在问我在哪里
My office is asking where I am.
他们说有个记者在四处查探
They say a reporter's been sniffing around.
申明一下 兰登洗清了
For the record, Langdon cleared you
你和威胁评估文件的所有牵连
of any involvement in the threat assessment file.
如果能有人能直接问我
Yeah, well, I could have told you that...
我会告诉你这个情况的
If somebody would have asked me,
而不是把我当作间谍一样对待
instead of treating me like some kind of spy.
这不是针对你 只是标准流程
It's not personal. It's just protocol.
是的 但感觉上就是这样
Right. It just feels that way.
很多以前我觉得不可能的事情
I mean, a whole lot of things make sense to me today
突然变成了事实
that didn't make sense to me yesterday.
我的总统先生和我在白宫最亲密的伙伴
My President, my closest friend in the White House...
都认为我叛国了
Both think I'm capable of treason.
情况危急 肖尔先生
These are dangerous times, Mr. Shore.
谢谢你的合作
But thank you for your cooperation.
不
No, no, no.
别跟我说你从来没吃过迷你汉堡
Don't tell me you've never had the sliders.
我都不知道那是什么
I didn't even know that they were a thing.
杰拉德 让托尼去做点
Gerald, have Tony rustle up
蒜泥蛋黄酱的日本牛肉小汉堡来
some of those wagyu sliders with aioli, would you?
不用这么劳民伤财了
I mean... That is not necessary.
亲爱的你 一定要尝一尝
Oh, necessary's got nothing to do with it, my dear.
好的 先生
Right away, sir.
这个工作可不容易
A lot of grief in this job.
有便宜不占太可惜了
You got to take the gravy wherever you can.
先生 我看了你的名单
Sir, I was looking at your list,
我很奇怪为什么布雷特·安布罗斯是内政部长
and I was wondering about Brett Ambrose for Interior.
他怎么了
Mm-hmm. What about him?
他在气候变化问题上举棋不定
Well, he's been inconsistent on climate change,
最近又反对一项减少石油钻井
and recently, he opposed a rule to reduce methane emissions
对公共土地的甲烷排放的提案
from oil drilling on public lands, so...
你让我想起了我的妻子伊莱恩
You know, you remind me so much of my wife, Elaine,
真的很神奇
it is downright eerie.
谢谢你
Thank you.
安布罗斯无疑是个难搞的老狐狸
Ambrose is a crusty old bird, no doubt.
但他业务熟练
But he understands business,
他希望美国可以真正做到能源独立
and he wants to make the United States truly energy-independent,
这需要一些让步
and that takes compromise.
这工作就是这么难做
Hell, that's what the job is all about.
除了迷你汉堡的福利以外
Except... when it comes to the sliders.
杰拉德
Gerald.
亚伦被调查局抓起来了吗
Aaron got brought in by the FBI?
应该是 我觉得他们好扯 没啥意义
Supposedly. I think it's crap. No story.
当然了
Oh, for sure.
我给他发短信了
I, uh, I texted him, though,
这样他就会有点心理准备
just so he's not caught off guard.
他回你了吗
Have you heard back?
还没有
Not yet.
你曾经想过
I mean, did you ever imagine
我们要面对联邦调查局和暗杀这些事吗
that we would be dealing with the FBI and assassinations?
这些所有的事
And all of this?
从来没想过
Not in a million years.
艾米丽·罗迪斯
Emily Rhodes.
谢谢你
Thank you.
要告诉我吗
Should I know?
还不行
Not yet.
好吧
All right.
这是世界上最伟大的演出
Greatest show on Earth.
民主 就是一场伟大的实验
Democracy... The grand experiment.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
俄罗斯在安理会决议会议上否决了纳鲁巴提案
Russia vetoed the Security Council vote on Naruba.
是的
Yes.
我想联席会议议员们肯定强调了
And I'm sure the Joint Chiefs have already emphasized
纳鲁巴在战略上毫无意义
that Naruba is strategically worthless.
那个国家的人民太穷了
People are so damn poor in that country
甚至都没有经济报告
that it doesn't even register on economic reports.
他们说了
They did.
所以归根结底是人民的问题
So it all comes down to people.
民生的问题
Human lives.
“整个世界上永远充斥着
"The eternal struggle between two principles...
正确与谬误之间的永恒斗争“
Right and wrong... Throughout the world."
亚伯拉罕·林肯
Abraham Lincoln.
想象一下他所必须具备的勇气
Imagine the courage he must have had...
为了人人平等的基本权利而抗争
Standing up for the basic rights of equality,
就算他深知这会导致手足相残
knowing he was gonna send brothers fighting brothers.
我听说海豹突击队前往纳萨尔执行任务之前
I hear you went to, uh, visit the SEAL team before they deployed
你去拜访了他们
on the Nassar mission.
是的
Yeah.
这是个高尚之举 但亲自去见
It's a noble gesture, but it does come at a cost...
那些你要派去送死的人 就是有代价的
Putting faces to the lives of the men you send to die.
我们失去了一个指挥官 麦克斯·克拉克森
We lost a commander... Max Clarkson.
每天我都会不禁想起他和他的家人
Not a day goes by that I don't think about him or his family.
最高统帅
Commander-in-Chief.
不只是个名号
It's not just a title.
而且是一份责任
It is a responsibility.
极其重大的责任
An awful responsibility.
你当时根本没有准备好
You were in no way prepared for it,
但你还是接手了
but you've taken it on.
可以说 你很勇敢
Bravely, I might add.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在你手握主宰着
And now you have the power to decide
他人的生杀大权
who lives...and who dies.
高处不胜寒
It's the loneliest job in the world.
- 总统先生  - 怎么了
- Mr. President.  - What is it?
总统先生 纳鲁巴发生了混乱
Sir, there's been a complication in Naruba.
我们刚收到情报
We just got Intel that
有十五名美国人道主义工作者
15 American humanitarian workers
被卡拉米的自卫队抓去做人质
have been taken hostage by Kalame's militia.
显然他把人质分别扣押在
Apparently, he's holding them in several
其护卫队中的几辆车里
different vehicles in his convoy.
我们不知道是哪一辆
We don't know which ones.
如果你继续发动无人机袭击
If you continue with this drone strike,
你杀死的不止是卡拉米和他的手下
you won't just be killing Kalame and his men.
还会杀死我们的国人
We'll be killing our own.
赶快走吧
Come on. Let's go.
都坐下吧
Keep your seats.
到底是怎么回事
What the hell happened?
我们怎么会不知道有美国公民
How could we not know that we had American citizens
在那个国家做自愿者
working as volunteers in the country?
他们曾是美国公民 总统先生
They were AMCIT, sir...
从未在大使馆登记过的美国公民
American citizens who never registered with an embassy.
我们是没法知道的 总统先生
We had no way of knowing, Mr. President.
知道他们的下落吗 是否受伤了吗
Do we know where they are? If they've been hurt?
不知道 只知道被关在卡拉米的护卫队里
No, only that they're being kept among Kalame's convoy
所以我们不能攻击他或他的手下
so we can't target him or his men.
与真主党挟持环球航空847航班时如出一辙
Same strategy Hezbollah used when they hijacked TWA 847.
1985年6月14日 环球航空847航班由雅典飞往意大利罗马 在地中海上空遭伊斯兰激进派份子劫持
把所有乘客撤离飞机
Took all the passengers off the plane,
将其分散在贝鲁特
spread them all around Beirut,
黎巴嫩港口城市
导致反击无法实行
making a counterattack impossible.
无人机还要多久才能到达阿鲁巴上空
How long till the UAVs are over Naruba?
不到一小时 总统先生
Less than an hour, sir.
汤姆 卡拉米的事
Tom, about Kalame...
我还没决定
I haven't decided yet.
你必须做出决定 而且要快
Well, you need to... And fast.
有人拿枪指着那些志愿者
Those volunteers have guns to their heads.
如果我们不袭击叛军
If we don't attack those rebel forces,
就会有人拿枪指着首都的
100,000 innocent civilians in the capital
十万名无辜平民
will have guns to their head, too.
我不知道该如何只解救十五人
I don't know how to justify 15 lives
而不管那十万人
over 100,000.
那不只是普通的十五个性命 总统先生
It's not just any 15 lives, Mr. President.
而是十五个美国人的性命 你的国民
It's 15 American lives... Your citizens.
你必须先对他们负责
You have a responsibility to them first.
那就要牺牲其他人的性命吗
At the expense of everyone else?
当然
Absolutely.
这和勇敢或是灵活没有关系
This isn't about bravery or mobility.
这是情报上的失误
This was a failure of intelligence.
卡拉米已经把你逼到了角落
Now Kalame's got you backed into a corner.
不 你要做的就是快速行动
No, what you have to do is act swiftly
确保我们的国人得以安全释放
to secure the safety and the release of our own.
然后你可以决定如何处置那些罪犯
Then you can decide what you want to do with that criminal.
你回来了
Hey, man. You back?
不不 马上就走
No, no, it's just a quick hit.
你怎么样 你没…
Oh, how you been? You haven't, uh...
你有段时间没回我短信了
You haven't returned my texts in a while.
一言难尽
Well, it's, uh... it's complicated.
你不是真的被联调局带走了吧
You weren't really with the FBI, were you?
赛斯 我累了
Look, uh, Seth, I'm tired.
没事 没事的
No, no, no, it's fine. Come on.
我知道你不想说
I mean, I know a non-answer when I hear one.
如果我感觉你有必要知道的话
Look, if I felt you needed to know something,
- 我会告诉你的  - 嗯哼 事实上
- I would tell you.  - Yeah, hey, look,
周围已经没有人会跟我说了
nobody talks to me around here anymore.
那这也让你的工作更轻松了 不是吗
Well, it makes your job a whole lot easier, doesn't it?
艾米丽怎么样了
How's Emily doing?
私人生活吗
Personally?
不 不是 我是说工作
No, no... on the job.
就很好啊 你了解艾米丽的
Just... Just great. I mean, you know Emily, right?
工作她很擅长
She... She'll get the job done.
虽然跟你的处理方式不一样 但她很优秀
Not the same way you do, but, yeah, she's good.
很好
Good.
给
Here.
这是什么
What's this?
读吧 发挥点你的魔力
Read it. It could use a bit of your magic.
好
Sure.
我知道你是对的
I know you're right.
只是我不知道如何
I-I don't know how to
冒着牺牲十万人的危险去救十五个人
potentially sacrifice 100,000 people to save 15.
我不知道该怎么做
I-I don't know how to do that.
有一个外交方案
Well, you know, there is a diplomatic option
可以把他们救出来
to get them out.
你买通他们
You buy them.
我们不与恐怖分子协商
We don't negotiate with terrorists.
我赞同这项政策
I agree with that policy.
还有其它的路可以走
Well, there are other cards to play.
津巴布韦现在面临着卡拉米案
You see, right now, Zimbabwe is sitting on $7 million
七百万美元的审查
of Kalame's cash.
财政部正以走私为名制裁他们
Treasury put sanctions on them for smuggling.
这笔钱现在挪不动窝
That money is not going anywhere right now.
所以如果我们解除对他们的制裁
So if we lift their sanctions
把卡拉米的资金换出来用
in exchange for them releasing Kalame's cash to him...
一旦我们的人回来了
Say we get our people back.
又有什么能阻止我翻脸不认人
What stops me from turning around
炸他个底朝天呢
and blowing him off the face of the planet?
因为你给了他承诺
Because you give him your word.
世界都知道你是个公平正直的人
The world knows that you're a square dealer,
是时候打这手牌了
and now's the time to play that card.
我讨厌这样
I hate this.
我也是
I hate it, too.
但这就是你生活的世界 总统大人
But that's the world you're living in, Mr. President.
有时候你不得不在坏主意和
Sometimes you have to decide between a bad choice
无路可走之间做出选择
and no choice at all.
如果我要这样做了
If I were to do this...
那具体要怎么做呢
how would it play out?
通过一个名叫奥斯汀·西尔万巴的人
Through a man named Austin Silwamba,
津巴布韦的一个中层外交官
a mid-level diplomat in Zimbabwe.
他是中情局特工 过去曾为我们效力
He's a CIA asset that I've used in the past.
你授权他 促成一笔交易
You authorize him to broker a deal
允许将我们的人带到安全位置去
allowing our people to be taken to safe passage,
送至撤离点
to an extraction point.
然后派直升机接走
Then you chopper them out.
要我打电话吗
Want me to make the call?
嗯
Yes.
总统先生
Mr. President?
艾娃 进来
Ava. Come in.
奥斯汀-西尔万巴刚下飞机了
Austin Silwamba has just landed.
嗯好 谢谢
Okay, good. Thank you.
艾伦-肖尔在外面 总统先生
Aaron Shore is outside, sir.
请让他进来
Oh. Please, send him in.
总统先生 要是我来的不是时候
Sir, if this is a bad time...
不不不 艾伦 请 请坐
No, no, no. Aaron, please. Please sit.
关于最近
I am sorry
你所遭受的一切 我深感抱歉
about everything that you've had to go through lately.
但我很开心你能回来
But I am so glad to have you back.
谢谢 总统先生 但
I appreciate that, sir, but...
我没有要回来
I'm not coming back.
你很生气
You're angry.
我理解
I understand.
换做是我 我也会
Uh... I would be, too.
但你要知道 特勤局与联调局的调查
But I need you to know that I had the Secret Service
只是为了洗清你的嫌疑
and the FBI investigating you to clear your name.
兰登的证词己为你正名
And Langdon's testimony did that.
亚伦 拜托
Aaron, please.
回来助我一臂之力吧
Come back and help me govern.
先生 我很肯定艾米丽也会很出色的
Sir, I'm sure Emily will do an excellent job,
但如今 我…
but right now, I-I-I...
我无法胜任这份工作了
I-I couldn't be as effective.
再也不能了
Not anymore.
我不明白为什么
I don't understand. Why?
关于我的休假 坊间物议沸腾
Rumor mills are buzzing about my taking leave.
传言说联调局对我进行了审问
Word's hit the street I was interrogated by the FBI.
政治即观感 这点你我都清楚
Now, politics is perception. We both know that.
我的名誉己受损
My reputation's been damaged.
亚伦 观念是可以改变的
Aaron, perceptions can be changed.
我会发表声明 澄清事实
I'll make a statement. I'll clear the air.
我不会接受你的辞呈
I won't accept your resignation.
恐怕您别无他选 总统先生
I'm afraid you have no choice, sir.
我们说话这会 赛斯正向媒体传达我的声明
Seth is distributing my statement to the press as we speak.
没有事先与我商量
Without talking to me.
无意冒犯
I mean no disrespect.
但保护你是我的首要职责
But it is my primary job to protect you...
即使利害因素是您的慈悲本性
Even from your most generous instincts.
总统先生
Sir, right now,
如今我于您的政府来说是个累赘
I'd be a liability to your administration.
您的幕僚长也绝对不能被爆出
The last thing you need is any hint of scandal
任何丑闻
from your chief of staff.
能为您服务是我这辈子最大的荣幸
Serving you has been the greatest honor of my life.
抱歉 先生
Please, sir.
无法挽回了吗
There isn't anything I can say?
是的 先生
No, sir.
亚伦 是我该感到荣幸才对
Aaron, the honor's been mine.
我让你失望了
I let you down and...
- 抱歉  - 没事 我刚要走
I'm sorry.  No, that's fine. I was just leaving.
再会
Sir.
总统先生
Mr. President...
先生
Sir?
抱歉 怎么了
Yes. I'm sorry.
西尔万巴正在与卡拉米谈判
Silwamba's negotiated with Kalame.
- 我们的人回来了吗  - 还没 先生
Did we get our people back?  Not yet, sir.
飞机仍在前往撤离点途中
Helicopters are on the way to the extraction point.
指挥行动中心正在实时直播
There's a live feed in command ops.
走吧
Let's go.
先生 首济市达卡路的卡车上装着我们的人
Sir, our people are in those trucks on the Soji Daka Road.
黑鹰直升机呢
Where are the Black Hawks?
正在降落 您从这里可以看到
They're putting down now. You can track it here.
先生 十五名志愿者己全部离开
Sir, all 15 volunteers are outbound.
他们自由了 先生
They're free, sir.
孔特雷拉斯将军 无人机还在首济上空吗
General Contreras, are the UAVs still above Soji?
我们正准备撤回无人机 总统先生
We're in the process of recalling them now, sir.
- 先等等  - 先生
Hold on for a second.  Sir?
可能你会认为这是荒谬之举
You're gonna probably think this is ridiculous,
但我曾是名城市规划师
but by trade, I was an urban planner.
我答应了卡拉米不攻击他的部队
The deal I made with Kalame was to not attack his forces.
但我可没说不炸基础设施
I didn't say anything about infrastructure.
我认为如果我们炸毁这两座桥
I think that if we were to attack these two bridges
还有南部这几个咽喉点
and these choke points down here in the south,
可使他的部队至少晚三到四天
we could stall his army from entering the capital
进入首都
by three, maybe even four days.
你同意吗
Do you agree with that assessment?
同意 先生
Yes, sir.
- 很好 行动吧  - 好 先生
Good. Take them out.  Yes, sir.
我是孔特雷拉斯将军
This is Contreras.
聪明
Smart.
你要怎么利用这段时间
What are you going to do with the time?
不是我要怎么利用
It's not what I'm gonna do with it.
是我让你怎么利用
It's what I want you to.
我需要你让俄罗斯人相信
I need you to convince the Russians
授权维和部队进驻
that it's in their best interest to authorize
对他们是最有利的
the peacekeeping force to move in.
以平民的身份吗
As a private citizen?
最好是以国务卿的身份
Preferably as Secretary of State.
我知道你已经退休了
I know that you've retired from public service,
但国家需要你
but your country needs you.
我需要你
I need you.
你给我找的这个麻烦
Hell, you helped me get into this mess.
不如帮我解决掉吧
You might as well help me get out.
我愿意出一箱威凤凰波本酒
Be more than happy to sweeten the deal
作为请你出山的筹码
with a case of Wild Turkey.
我得承认
Well...I got to admit,
天天看着我的牛群
I have been getting a little tired
都有点厌倦了
of looking at my cattle all day.
总统先生
Mr. President...
一言为定
it's a deal.
谢谢 总统先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
目标已锁定 先生
Target is acquired, sir.
准确击中 目标被击毁
We have good strike. Target neutralized.
好
All right.
请在这签字
Just sign here, please.
亚伦
Aaron.
你接下来有什么打算
So, what's next?
我还没想这么远
I haven't gotten that far yet,
但我会通知你的
but... I'll let you know.
我会尽量做得和你一样出色
Well, I'll try and do the job as well as you did.
不
No.
要比我更出色
Do better.
我们有太多问题悬而未决
We have so many questions left unanswered.
显然 我们还不知道
Obviously, we still don't know
在政府中可以信任谁
who we can trust in the government.I know.
我知道
I know.
我一直在想那通让你做指定幸存者的电话
I keep on thinking about the Designated Survivor call.
如果不是兰登没打 又会是谁呢
And if Langdon didn't make it, then who did?
我要靠你帮我查清楚
I'm relying on you to find out.
我得专心治国
I need to focus on governing.
我要带领这个国家走出这场可怕的悲剧
I need to lead this country back from this terrible tragedy.
你还愿意帮我吗
Are you still up for this?
总统先生 我还没开始大展身手呢
Mr. President, I haven't even gotten started yet.
很好
Good.
这是一项取消所有
This is a Presidential Finding
联调局对你的监视的总统令
absolving you from all FBI supervision.
没有另行通知的情况下 你直接向我汇报
Until further notice, you'll be reporting to me.
里特探员是你的联络人
Agent Ritter will be your liaison.
法索探员呢
And Agent Foerstel?
他听你差遣
He'll be at your disposal.
你会有秘密的办公室
You'll be provided with a secure office
和通讯方式
with secure communications.
没人知道你在做什么 明白吗
Nobody will know what you're doing. Understood?
明白 先生
Yes, sir.
威尔士探员 我在此授权
Agent Wells, I hereby authorize you
你可以使用任何
to use whatever means necessary,
不违反美国宪法的必要手段
within the Constitution of the United States of America,
找到参与这场阴谋的人
to find the people involved in this conspiracy
让他们受到法律制裁
and bring them to justice.
我不会让您失望的 总统先生
I will not let you down, Mr. President.
■
微信扫描
上方二维码
关注TV哔
一起哔哔哔